





A1-7 Comfort Zone Balewadi, Pune, India



Full Stack Java Developer

I am having total 5 years of experience in Java Technology and 3+ years of relevant experience in IT industry. Currently working as a Senior Software Engineer in Payments domain. If you are looking for a candidate who will go the extra mile to get things done, and learn new things then I am the one.

Nikita Upadhyaya

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Volante Technologies Pvt Ltd

11/2020 - Present Banking Project

Pune

Role & Project Description

• We provide payment processing solutions to our customers with our own designed frameworks. Currently my role is to handle a team of 4 people and take part in all technical solutioning and development activities.

Software Engineer BNT Soft Pvt Ltd

12/2018 - 11/2020

Foreign Currency Exchange Project

Pune

Roles & Project Description

 Providing wallet based system to send money to anyone around the globe in any currency on current foreign exchange rate. My role was to design well designed, efficient and testable code.

Java Trainer

FreeLancing

Wendy School Junior College(01/17-09/17) & Madhav Institute of Technology & Science(08/2015-08/2016)

Role & Project Description

 Devise technical training programs according to organisational requirements. Produce training schedules and classroom agenda. Determine course content according to objectives.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer Certification

Seed Infotech Pvt Ltd

07/2018 - 11/2018 Pune

Masters Of Technology in IT

Madhav Institute of Technology & Science

08/2014 - 08/2016

80.8

Thesis Tonic

• A Novel Approach for CBIR using Color Strings and Multi-Fusion Feature Method.

Bachelor Of Engineering in CS

ITM Universe

08/2010 - 08/2014 76.7

12th ISC

Wendy School Junior College

2014 6183

10th ICSE

Wendy School Junior College

2010 84.25

SKILLS



PUBLICATIONS

A Novel Approach for CBIR using Color Strings and Multi-Fusion Feature Method (08/2015 - 08/2016)

https://scholar.google.com/scholar? cluster=8768364498790063918&hl=en&oi=scholarr

An exhaustive survey on nature inspired optimization algorithms (08/2015 - 08/2016)

http://modul.repo.mercubuana-yogya.ac.id/modul/files/openjournal/JournalOfInformation/11_168.pdf

A review: Relating low level features to high level semantics in cbir (08/2015 - 08/2016)

https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/740d/c8c5839762fbc0beb996a0fe2674d 1ff9db8.pdf

Nature Inspired Optimization Algorithms: An Insight to Image Processing Applications (08/2015 - 08/2016)

https://scholar.google.com/scholar? cluster=4472573534646521316&hl=en&oi=scholarr

ACHIEVEMENTS

Rising Star - BNT Soft Pvt Ltd (11/2019)

Achieved Certificate of Merit in British English Course affiliated by Cambridge University (2012)

Achieved Certification of City Rank (10) and State Rank (809) in 12th National Science Olympiad (2009)

Achieved Certification of 76th Percentile in International Assessments For Indian Schools (English) by The University Of New South Wales (2004)

Achieved 1 st Position in International Level Environment Education Programme (2008)

KEY STRENGTHS

Strong Analytical & Logical programming skills

Strong Debugging, Analysis & Troubleshooting skills

Keen at learning new concepts

Working well under pressure and communicating ideas clearly and effectively and good team player.